Scott Hansen 41 70th Way NE Fridley, Mn 55432 651-357-5757 s.hansen18@gmail.com

Professional Summary or Objective

Having worked 5 years as desktop support, and 6 years as a field technician, I was given an opportunity to change career paths and focus on Cyber Security, something that has always interested me. I am looking forward to a career in Cyber Security and also furthering my knowledge in this field.

Salary Requirements

I believe that with my experience and knowledge it is reasonable to ask 60,000 per year. However I am open to negotiations at the time of being hired.

Education

Currently enrolled in the UofMN Cybersecurity bootcamp. During this course, I have further developed my networking knowledge as well as gained skills in cyber security. I have been exposed to numerous concepts, applications, and operating systesms. Currently I have worked with containers, Microsoft Azure, Microsoft active directory, Kali Linux, Metasploit, WireShark, Elk Stack.

Please feel free to explore my GitHub as it details the this class, it can be found at: https://github.com/shansen18/BootCamp/blob/main/Readme.md

During this time I was in this class, I have also deployed Security Onion SEIM on my personal netowork. Worked on many CTF's on CTFlearn, TryHackMe, Hack the Box, and Vulnhub. I have also setup a virtual lab on my personal laptop.

A.A. degree in Network Development, Brown College, graduation March 2008 Graduated with distinction (3.75 GPA)

Professional Experience

CenturyLink\Lumen, Brooklyn Center Mn

Broadband Technician March 2015 to April 2021

At Centurylink I was working as a broadband technician, installing DSL, Fiber, and Pots into residential, and small businesses. I also troubleshot and repaired the copper and fiber lines used in providing internet and phone services. Depending on the job, this may have included rewiring or installation of phone jacks. Running new cat5/6 wire and terminating them with rj45/rj11 ends, depending on the use. Finding damaged to the line and repairing it, either on premise or in the field. This career allows me to work independently from other technicians and with little contact from supervisors. Every day I have multiple face to face contacts with

our customers, in order to resolve any issues, or to install services, this requires me to translate technical terms and processes to customers who may not know the terms or processes. This part of the job focused mainly on soft skills.

Yada Systems Inc, Roseville

Technical Support, March 2010 to September 2014

I worked as a help desk technician providing phone support for Axalta's ColorNet Automotive Paint retrieval system software, as well as Axalta's ProfitNet Body Shop management system software and effectively logging the calls. Other support includes hardware troubleshooting of CPU's, printers and custom equipment such as paint scale, and the X-Pert Pour system, and diagnosing any defective hardware. I also directed customers on how to Peer to Peer networks, and install our software in server and client machines (in both a peer to peer setup and domain setup). Logging the calls, and following up on any unresolved issues. Between calls I worked on setting up an internal help web-page and installing it in a Server 2008 IIS7 environment, learning HTML, Java, CSS, and WIKI syntax as I created the page.

Certification:

Power Limited Technician

Military Service

Army National Guard, July 2001 to July 2009

Rank: E4

MOS: 15-T Blackhawk Helicopter Technician

References:

Jason Archelleta

Technician TDS (612)817-6873

David Munez

Broadband Technician CenturyLink (612)481-8603

Dave Burkhardt

Central Office Technician CenturyLink 952-475-4828 612-861-6275